Kyle Sokolis

Alexandria, VA

703-598-9301 kyle.sokolis@gmail.com

From a submarine in the depths of the ocean to the front lines of customer interfaces, I give life to the ordinary experience ensuring every stakeholder is armed with the ammunition they need to bring a compelling story to life through data.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Data Science Immersive Program

2018 - 2019

General Assembly

Washington, D.C.

- Data Cleaning/Exploration Python, Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, SQL
- Machine learning and Regression/Classification based Modeling Scikit-Learn and Statsmodels
- Natural Language Processing (NLP) SpaCy, NLTK
- Webscraping/Data Mining Requests, BeautifulSoup
- Visualization/Analysis Matplotlib, Seaborn, Tableau

Field Service Engineer

2016 - 2018

Fujifilm Medical Systems USA

Washington, D.C.

- Primarily was responsible for the installation, calibration, inspection, preventive maintenance, troubleshooting, and repair of digital imaging equipment, including electrical, mechanical and software components.
- Established and maintained a high level of customer satisfaction with all products, support and service.
- Trained customers on the basic operation and use of the digital radiography equipment.
- Managed inventory, kept accurate records, and returned unused and failed parts promptly.

Biomedical Engineering Intern

2015 - 2016

Children's National Medical Center

Washington, D.C.

- Primarily performed preventative and corrective maintenance on Medfusion 4000 syringe pumps and Alaris/ Carefusion Medley 8015/8001 PC/Module.
- Professionally conducted interdepartmental communication between the biomedical engineering department and the nursing staff for the safe and efficient procurement of the 2400+ pumps on site.
- Ensured follow-up communications on this work and any other assigned responsibilities.
- Documented and maintained records of all work activities in the computerized maintenance management (CMMS) software.
- Facilitated training for incoming interns as well as current biomedical engineering technicians who were not familiar with the different pumps procedures and operations.

Data Center Technician - Level 2

2013 - 2014

Amazon Web Services

Chantilly, VA

- Installed, configured, maintained and would troubleshoot to resolve all Linux OS related issues.
- Coached junior staff members on standard operating procedures.
- Advanced understanding of IT hardware concepts.
- Solid understanding of Linux/Unix Administrating.

Submarine Fire Control Technician

2008 - 2013

United States Navy

- Experienced with Linux systems in a Tactical Weapons Computer Work Center on a National Strategic Asset.
- Diagnosed and performed hardware repairs on computerized Tactical Weapons Systems.
- Facilitated change management projects.
- Resolved network issues and ensured redundancy system success.
- Managed quality assurance documentation and tasks.
- Provided technical expertise to senior command officials to aid in ship safety decision making.

Kyle Sokolis

Alexandria, VA 703-598-9301 kyle.sokolis@gmail.com

Education

Catholic University of America 2015 - 2016 Biomedical Engineering Major Washington, D.C.

Northern Virginia Community College 2014 - 2014 General Studies Major Alexandria, VA

United States Navy

2008 - 2013 Great Lakes, IL Goose Creek, SC Groton, CT Kings Bay, GA Norfolk, VA Portsmouth, VA

References

Jeffery Hooper Director of Biomedical Engineering Children's National Medical Center 410-991-0910

Brett Moore Zone Digital X-Ray Engineer Fujifilm Medical Systems USA 717-979-5218

LTCDR Larry Duran SQDRN 20 Weapons Officer U.S. Navy 912-467-2024